<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Election Analytics Blog</title>
    <link>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Election Analytics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 - 10/3/22 - Incumbency &amp; Experts</title>
      <link>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-10-03-week-4-10-3-22-incumbency-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-10-03-week-4-10-3-22-incumbency-experts/</guid>
      <description>Model Update This week, I will be taking a different approach to vote-share prediction than before. This will be my first week incorporating district-level predictions. District-level predictions all for more nuance, but suffer from a lack of commonly accessible data (a large issue for linear regression models). To begin this district analysis, I will focus on incumbency and expert predictions.
As always, scratch work can be found here.
Incumbency Incumbency has been widely shown to be a large predictor of electoral outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 - 2022-09-26: Poll Data</title>
      <link>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-26-week-3-2022-09-26-poll-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-26-week-3-2022-09-26-poll-data/</guid>
      <description>Modeling Update For this week’s modeling update, I begin looking at the role of polling data in improving modeling outcomes. To investigate the role, I will start out with a base model (including economic factors and incumbency) and then add to it based on the polling data. I will be taking a look at predicting house-incumbent (the party with the plurality of house seats) two-party popular vote share.
As always, you can find my scratchwork here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 - 2022-09-19: Economic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-19-week-2-2022-09-19-economic-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-19-week-2-2022-09-19-economic-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello everyone! For this week’s blog, we’re going to be taking a look at how various different economic indicators (specifically GDP, RDI, CPI, and Unemployment) produce different outcomes for the 2022 midterm elections.
Before diving into the details of these different models, I wanted to mention, if you’re interested in seeing some of the “scratch work” for how I come to these analyses, please feel free to view my weekly notebooks on my Github (this week’s can be found here here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 - 9/15/22</title>
      <link>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-15-week-1-9-15-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joshua-doolan.github.io/GOV1347-Blog-Posts-F22/post/2022-09-15-week-1-9-15-22/</guid>
      <description>View my week 1 blog here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
